Yamato
Space Battleship
Soldiers of Love
Are you alright ? Are you hurt ?
I’m fine. Thank you.
That’s good.
I don’t know where my brother is…
Eh ?
…or my mom…
…or dad…!
Don't worry. They must have
gone to the mine already.
I’ll look for them later.
Really ?
Sure thing.
Now, let’s go.
What’s wrong ?
Yamato…
Eh ?
Brother…
Huh ?
If you’re still alive, head to the bridge !
Commander, this is Furuhashi,
these Gatlantis soldiers are…
We still have many options to continue our fight…
…but I want to avoid further losses on both sides.
We’ll surrender.
Surrender ?
What does surrender mean ?
To acknowledge defeat and end a battle.
You are…
You want to end the battle ?
Then die.
Fight and die.
That will bring peace to this planet.
They truly are demons.
Commander Hijikata…
Fight and die ?
Fine by me !
But I can't involve civilians.
Use that to escape.
That's impossible.
That can't carry all of us.
Perhaps just the children…?
With kids on board, we can't fly
wildly to break out of the enemy siege.
Exactly.
That's why we have to place our bets on you.
Wha…?
Wait. Why me ?
Is it because I’m a woman…?!
Bring a rescue ship to the pits of hell.
Only you can do it.
You owe me, Commander.
I’m…
Go, Nagakura !
I'm not running away.
I'll bring a rescue ship for sure.
Here's a visual of the enemy fleet just
before Warrant Officer Nagakura warped in.
Gatlantis…
It's almost like they're right on our doorstep.
Why didn't we notice them ?
I believe there's an old Garmillas
logistics base on the 11th planet.
Yeah, we’ve been developing the planet for the last 3 years, using the artificial sun we set up during the previous war.
There must be a great number of
Earth and Garmillas civilian settlers there.
The battle began more than 40 hours ago.
Communications have been out for a while.
No survivors then ?
This is a serious matter.
I didn't expect Gatlantis to
advance to the Solar System so quickly.
Then why do you want us to stay out of this ?
The size of the enemy is too large
for the Yamato to handle by itself.
I want you to continue your trip to Telezart.
But then…
What about rescuing survivors ?
We’ll do our best, of course.
As soon as our dialogue with Garmillas is over...
...we'll make our move to recapture the 11th planet.
Just pass by ?
We aren't going to rescue them ?
Right.
Apparently those are HQ's orders.
I've heard that Garmillas has a
strong influence on this expedition.
HQ’s worried about them ?
No way.
Truth be told, we have
one Gammie on the ship.
With maximum acceleration, this is the
shortest route from our current coordinates.
If we warp every 16 hours, the Yamato should be able to get to the zone where the message was sent in 29 days.
As you can see, the 11th planet is way off the route.
Since the Yamato's objective is to learn
the truth of Teresa's message ASAP…
Our objective is to save lives…
…by responding to the message from Telezart.
That's my understanding.
H…hey.
Therefore, I find it contradictory that we'd
abandon drowning people right before our eyes.
I can’t accept that.
You are…
You saved my life, Lieutenant.
Why are you here ?
Only high-ranking officers are…
Is there any difference between Garmillas and
Earth when it comes to saving our own people ?
I might sound cruel, but it's been too long.
There won't be any survivors.
We won't know unless we go there.
In fact, one person escaped.
This argument has no merit.
I want to hear the Acting Captain’s decision.
The situation makes it dangerous
for the Yamato to charge in by itself.
But that's nothing compared
to the situation at Planet Balan.
I’ll follow the tactics Captain Okita used back then.
Kodai…
The warp out location is the mid-point between the artificial sun and the planet surface.
That’s too risky.
If we force the ship to warp out near the surface…
…the wave motion engine will be temporarily disabled because of gravity damage.
It'll take 2 hours to resume.
During that time, the shock cannons
and wave motion barrier won't…
I’m aware of that.
Quite decisive.
That tactic is definitely like Okita’s.
But the Yamato’s objective is not to retrieve dead bodies by taking such a risk, is it ?
She escaped the battlefield against all odds.
We can only pay that off…
…if we believe that there are still survivors.
All hands, maintain Class-1 battle
stations and prepare to warp !
Commence the 11th planet rescue operation !
If we can’t rescue drowning people right before our eyes, we won’t be able to save the universe from a crisis.
Yamamoto Akira didn't say that.
That's how she sounded to me.
Probably the others, too.
So, whoever sees Teresa’s vision will become deaf ?
Maybe.
Or it's because we're on the Yamato.
The Yamato currently has a serious weakness.
It's different from the previous journey.
You should know what it is.
What do you mean ?
As an adviser, I have to mediate the risk.
Huh ?!
The Acting Captain has approved of this.
You heard him.
Guys, re-enter the call signs.
Don't shoot down a Garmillas
craft from behind by mistake.
Roger that.
What's on your mind ?
Since we've decided to do this,
let's get it done quickly and move on.
Ten seconds to warp…
…nine…
…eight…
…seven…
Commander…guys…
…six...
...five…
Hang in there.
…four…
I'm coming back with the Yamato.
…three…
…two…
…one.
Warp !
Warp.
Am I…alive ?
Commander !
This way.
Commander.
Where’s the Yamato ?
Brother told me the Yamato
can beat these guys easily.
The Yamato will come for sure.
Gravity interference wave detected.
A possible warp out.
It's too early for the 8th Task Force to arrive.
Location ?
Unable to pin point because
it's within the planet's gravity field.
Expand the search range and
include the surface ! Hurry !
Survivors confirmed.
Eliminating hostiles.
It came.
It really came !
Yamato…
Shima, can you hover over that bridge ?
The air current is too strong.
I'll use the rocket anchors to stabilize.
I'll leave it to you.
Nanbu.
Yes ?
Cooperate with the military personnel on the bridge and pick up all the refugees.
You take charge.
Roger.
Over here ! Hurry !
We're saved !
Enemy fleet approaching from 4 o’clock.
So they came.
Kato, stop the advancement of the enemy fleet.
Ignore those horseshoe crabs.
I got you.
That bastard isn't too bad.
Commander !
What’s wrong ?
One got through.
Alright, I’ll just…
It’s mine.
Enemy destroyer approaching from behind.
All refugees are aboard.
Retrieve the rocket anchors.
Yamato, take off !
Dammit, I can't stop it.
Commander…
What the hell ?
What's wrong with the Yamato ?
Is it running away ?
SAM launcher, fire !
Type-3 shell, fire !
Huh ? What's this ?
There's a massive dimensional distortion in orbit.
What ?
Your Majesty, our almighty Emperor,
I have pleasure in reporting that…
…our 8th Task Force has reached the Zol system as planned.
That’s…
What the…?
The Yamato…
Episode 6
Deadly Battle on the 11th Planet
Tawamureru yuragu tsuki no kagami
The reflection of the moon is blurry and capricious
Kodai Susumu:
Shima Daisuke:
Sanada Shiro:
Nanbu Yasuo:
Aihara Yoshikazu:
Ohta Kenjiro:
Tokugawa Hikozaemon:
Saijo Miki:
Kato Saburo:
Yamamoto Akira:
Shinohara Hiroki:
Ono Daisuke
Suzumura Kenichi
Otsuka Hochu
Akabane Kenji
Kokubun Masato
Chiba Yuki
Mugihito
Moriya Satomi
Hosoya Yoshimasa
Tanaka Rie
Hirata Daisuke
Saito Hajime:
Nagakura Shiori:
Furuhashi Nagakura:
Kurata Masaru:
Todou Heikuro:
Hijikata Ryu:
Serizawa Kotetsu:
Robert Ledrous:
Katsuragi Touko:
Keyman:
Cosmodart:
Goenitz:
Iry:
Officer A:
Officer B:
Tochi Hiroki
Amagai Kazusa
Takashina Toshitsugu
Yoshikai Kiyohito
Kojima Toshihiko
Ishizuka Unsho
Genda Tessho
Hashi Takaya
Kaida Yuko
Kamiya Hiroshi
Kawai Toshiya
Umetsu Hideyuki
Aoki Shiki
Yano Masaaki
Fujinuma Kento
Kokoro tokasu yuubina kami no itazura
Graceful God's mischief mesmerizes my heart
Uchi ni himeta awai omoide ni
There's a faint memory hidden within
Iki wo fukikomu no michite yukumade
Breathe life into it until it's full
Hibiku anata no mune no kodou wo
I hear a heartbeat echoing through
Watashi hitori janai
I am not alone
Saewataru sora ni inori
I pray to the wide open sky
Atarashii ichinichi no maku ga aketeyuku
The curtain opens on a brand new day
Preview
There's so many of them !
Total 15,000 and counting.
That shape… Could that be…
Supernova ?
I just want to do what’s normal.
Kodai, fire the wave motion gun !
Episode 07
Drastic Turn! Flash of the Wave Motion Gun